Contact

josh.holbrook@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jfhbrook (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Site Reliability Engineering asyncio
Twisted

Josh Holbrook

Software Engineering Leader with Broad Experience in Web, Data and Site Reliability

Wasilla, Alaska, United States

Summary

Hello! I'm a software engineer with over 12 years experience. I've worked across a broad range of specialties - backend service development, data engineering, reliability engineering, even frontend - and across many industries - PaaS/SaaS, digital media, adtech, and more.

My favorite languages are Rust, Python and TypeScript. But I've also spent time with JavaScript, Scala, Bash, Go, and many flavors of SQL. I've also deployed to AWS, GCS, DigitalOcean and Kubernetes, and have collected and surfaced site telemetry with DataDog, New Relic and Honeycomb. But recently I've been growing in technical leadership skills, such as mentorship, design, and consensus-driving.

While I love to swing a hammer and push raw code, my passions lie with strategy and tactics - how to incrementally evolve software over the course of the entire lifecycle. I'm very interested in the problems inherent in maintaining legacy systems and incrementally developing them towards the modern systems we want.

I have a history of developing open source software. My most successful projects are Ecstatic, a static fileserving middleware for Node.js, and pyee, an implementation of EventEmitters for Python inspired by Node.js. I have many more projects - most of them are on GitHub. My current passion project is learning how to write a shell-oriented BASIC interpreter.

I was born and raised in Alaska. I went to college at the University of Alaska Fairbanks and graduated in 2011 with a M.S. in Mechanical Engineering. My thesis was on heat transfer in snow. While I've lived in many places - including Brooklyn for 8 years - I currently call Wasilla, Alaska my home.

My resume may be found at https://github.com/jfhbrook/resume .

Experience

Procore Technologies
Staff Software Engineer
August 2022 - January 2024 (1 year 6 months)

Wasilla, Alaska, United States

My role was extremely varied at Procore - I drove SRE engagements, acted as on-call for core systems, offered operational support, became a subject matter expert on SLOs, developed resiliency automations, and even wrote ETL in TypeScript. But above all, this role taught me a lot about collaboration and technical discourse in challenging social environments - and frankly, emotional regulation. Throughout, I remained a strong mentor and was always been game to roll up my sleeves and grab a hammer.

Eaze Staff Engineer October 2021 - August 2022 (11 months) Remote

Most of my time at Eaze was spent shaving yaks - that is, those infrastructure tasks that distract engineers from their immediate goals. I contributed OpenTelemetry support to boltzmann, our core JavaScript/TypeScript framework, so that we could migrate off Honeycomb's beeline libraries. I also wrote the base migration tooling for our MSSQL database, including patching and contributing to golang-migrate. Finally, I spent a lot of time analyzing the greater themes of our development lifecycles so that I could best advise management on process and hiring.

DoubleVerify
Staff Data Engineer
July 2020 - October 2021 (1 year 4 months)
New York, New York, United States

I worked with DV's Social Integrations - Brand Safety team. When I arrived, we had the challenge of quickly building greenfield products using all-new gitlab-based infrastructure - and not only did we ship an alpha of our Facebook brand suitability product pipelines to production in less than four sprints; but over my tenure we built out a full data engineering framework and the seeds of a true platform. My role on the team involved technical and architectural leadership; mentoring other team members, and being the glue that keeps people from

getting blocked technically. Our stack: GCP, BigQuery, Kafka, Python, attrs and mypy, with deployments to Kubernetes using Helm and GitLab CI.

Self-employed Independent Sabbatical January 2020 - June 2020 (6 months) Brooklyn, New York, United States

I took some time off to work on some passion projects, work on myself, and learn about what makes me happy. Software projects over this time include a Jupyter kernel written in JavaScript and running in Electron; teaching myself PowerShell; and a PowerShell module for installing Emacs and running the Emacs daemon in the background.

Squarespace Senior Software Engineer July 2019 - January 2020 (7 months) New York, New York, United States

I joined Squarespace's Financial Products team as a data engineer, working on pipelines and reporting for accounting reports on cash flow, tax remission and ASC606 revenue recognition. While there, I investigated and addressed material production issues with reporting and ingestions, developed bridge reports when issues were discovered after a close, designed and instituted an on-call process and rotation, made improvements to development tooling and CI pipelines to increase the velocity of developing and merging code changes, and updated database permission and role management tooling to improve the velocity and reliability of staging deploys and production releases. I also collaborated on multiple RFCs, including a proposal to onboard billing and payments onto Squarespace's Data Vault based reference architecture, and multiple proposals to improve the architecture of their financial reporting systems. We worked mostly with Python, Airflow, PostgreSQL and Kubernetes.

Gizmodo Media Group Senior Developer September 2016 - May 2019 (2 years 9 months) New York, New York, United States

I worked on GMG's data/analytics platforms and products, using Python, Redshift, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Spark/EMR, Scala/Play, Docker, spreadsheets (both Excel and gsheets) and even some Javascript. This involved aspects of data warehousing/ingestion and pipelines, analytics tracking, some sysadmin and devops work, a dash of backend services and as far as GMG had it, big (medium) data and (simple) recommendation systems.

Condé Nast Software Developer February 2014 - August 2016 (2 years 7 months) New York, New York, United States

When I first joined Condé Nast, they were just starting to roll out the early versions of Copilot, their in-house content management system that now runs the majority of their sites. I worked on API services for Copilot (core and otherwise), using Node.js, MongoDB and Solr. This included being on-call, working with Jenkins and Hieradata, and later Cloudformation templates and Codedeploy bundling scripts when we switched from Savvis to AWS. I'm also partially responsible for the relationships system used in Copilot 2.x, for better or worse.

i.TV Software Developer August 2013 - November 2013 (4 months) Provo, Utah Area

i.TV was a "second screen" TV/mobile social media startup whose products included a legacy TV Guide app, the Wiiu's TV app, and the unreleased flagship, TVTag. I left shortly after they acquired GetGlue. While I was there, I worked on backend systems using Coffeescript/Node.js, MongoDB and RabbitMQ; as well as a dash of front-end, mostly bugfixes in Angular.js for an app that was being used to create curated content synchronized with live TV in near-real time.

Nodejitsu, Inc. Head of Support June 2011 - November 2012 (1 year 6 months)

Nodejitsu was a Node.js platform as a service startup. I managed Nodejitsu's support staff, interacted with Nodejitsu's infrastructure to fix people's support requests (including SSH and tailing logs), and did tons of maintenance and bugfixing to Nodejitsu's open source libraries and internal tools (even creating some myself). I was as much a junior developer/junior sysadmin as I was a support engineer. I mostly worked with Node.js and CouchDB. Due to the nature of the startup and the time at which it happened, the vast majority of Nodejitsu's tech was in-house.

University of Alaska Fairbanks Research Assistant September 2010 - May 2011 (9 months)

I researched measuring anisotropic thermal conductivity in snow with needle probes (and got paid to write my master's thesis).

Education

University of Alaska Fairbanks

Master of Science (MS), Mechanical Engineering · (2005 - 2011)